# SHANE ABRAHAM

Dubai, UAE | +971 56 2463263 | Age: 21 | shaneabh777@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

### **Professional Profile**

Highly motivated software developer with experience in various programming languages, including C, C++, Java, and Python. Accomplished two successful internships and known for delivering projects with creative solutions. Recognized by the UAE government with a golden visa for outstanding academic achievement with a GPA of 3.8+. Possesses strong problem-solving skills, an ability to work efficiently in fast-paced environments, and a passion for continuous learning. Experienced in project management methodologies such as waterfall and agile, as well as SDLC. Committed to delivering high-quality results and driven to achieve success through responsible decision-making and a unique approach to problem-solving.

## Education

### Middlesex University Dubai (2019-2022)

Bachelor of Computer Systems Engineering

- First-class honors (4.0 GPA)
- Successfully developed and implemented an Android application, resulting in a Grade 1 for the final year individual project.
- Contributed to a Runner-Up finish in a FinTech Technovation competition while managing a team of four.
- Demonstrated strong leadership and teamwork skills through diverse group projects.
- Familiarity with both waterfall and agile project management methodologies.

#### Our Own High School (2004-2019)

#### **High School**

- 89% in Math, Physics, and Chemistry and 87% in Computer Science.
- 87.8% overall in 12<sup>th</sup> grade (CBSE)

## Experience

### ePROMIS Solutions LLC, Dubai

Aug 2022 – Oct 2022

#### Software Tester

- Worked with content to improve the reach of the company through different social media platforms.
- Queried data from SQL and performed data analysis and
- Designed websites using JavaScript, HTML, and tailwind.
- Worked with senior staff to understand the workflow process of the organization.

## Fly Dubai (Internship)

Nov 2022 – Feb 2023

- Acquired knowledge and expertise in software development best practices and coding standards.
- Developed a REST API using a structured spring boot application and gained experience in API request interception to check headers.
- Practiced performing CRUD operations in MongoDB and implementing Redis-based commands.
- Utilized MongoDB as a cache to improve application performance.
- Extracted and transferred code from a big project to a new project, and exposed the information collected from the database as an API.
- Acquired the ability to create and document APIs, including understanding Lombok and creating technical documentation.
- Expanded skillset by learning Flutter to add additional UI features to a Big Data dashboard.

# SHANE ABRAHAM

Dubai, UAE | +971 56 2463263 | Age: 21 | shaneabh777@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

## Middlesex University Dubai

Sept 2021 – Apr 2022

- Final year individual project: Designed and built an Android app to improve financial capability; integrated APIs, managed cloud-database using firebase, developed real-time stock price alert system; enforced agile framework and tracked project progress using Microsoft Excel
- Game Development with JavaFX: Developed a multi-player networking game using JavaFX and scene builder; utilized sockets and multithreading for player connection and exchange of messages via TCP; applied client-server architecture.
- Coursework experience: Implemented library search system in C++ using Binary Search Tree algorithm; researched topics in Mobile Edge Computing vs Software-defined Networking, Ad-hoc networks, and financial capabilities; gained experience in Linux OS and automated water pumping system using Raspberry Pi.

#### **Student Learning Assistant**

- Supported professors and students during practical sessions, fostering an attentive learning environment that led to a 60% reduction in programming errors.
- Facilitated students' understanding of VHDL programming and circuit design, while encouraging their exploration of subject-related opportunities.
- Demonstrated exceptional ability in supporting students in enhancing their subject comprehension.

Personal Projects

Apr 2022 - Present

- Developed dynamic web application using Java Servlets, HTML5, and JavaScript with MVC architecture to analyze stock market information.
- Utilized REST APIs to obtain financial data in real-time and implemented CRUD operations on a MySQL database with data normalization to minimize redundancy.
- Designed and developed multiple web applications, including CRM, real estate property listing, and an interactive dashboard, using React JS and CSS frameworks such as Bootstrap and Tailwind
- Conducted data analysis using Pandas and NumPy to sort and filter expenses and built a Flask API to send data to
  websites
- Designed and developed a web-based price alert system in Django using JavaScript and researched and implemented both static and dynamic web pages in Django.

#### Expo 2020, Volunteer

Jan 2022

- Provided comprehensive information and guidance to visitors during Expo 2020, honing my communication and interpersonal skills.
- Effectively monitored and supervised the assigned site to maintain the safety and security of all individuals, while gaining valuable insights into the cultural diversity of the UAE.
- Trained and mentored new volunteers in managing visitor relations and directing them to their desired locations, contributing to the smooth operation of the event.

## **Professional skills**

- Python, Java, C++, Django, Flask, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SQL, NoSQL, React JS, Stimulsoft.
- Strong leadership, communication, and collaboration skills
- Fluent in reading, writing, and speaking English.
- Skilled in advanced critical thinking, problem-solving, and logic.
- Capable of developing and explain ideas and methods clearly.
- Proficient in MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, and MS word.
- Ability to multitask and work in fast-paced environments.
- Certified in Google Analytics and skilled in UI designing using Figma.